Assistant Manager - BA Continuum India Pvt. Ltd.

+91-9582785371 □

Delhi, India 🛇

Seasoned Analytics professional with over half a decade of extensive experience in diverse industries including ITES, ecommerce and banking. Responsible for building analytics capabilities within strategic marketing, digital, customer analytics, risk and compliance. Designed and implemented multiple statistical and machine learning capabilities helping institutions like HCL Technologies, Snapdeal.com and Bank of America, therein contributing to the field of innovation and strategy.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager - Innovation & Machine Learning Global Risk & Compliance, BA Continuum India Pvt. Ltd. Gurgaon, India

08/2017 - Present

Key responsibilities handled for Bank's OPEX:

Reviewing processes and identifying problem area

Designing solution framework (end to end execution plans), POCs and tools procurement

Bridge/narrow gaps in E2E process implementation

Re-design/automated mid-size (less than150 FTE) processes to strengthening execution and seamless integration of processes Defining risk framework, BCP and continuous monitoring methods Key strategic implementations for business transformation:

- Transformation of Enterprise Independent Testing

About EIT a 6k+ employee, aims to test 450+ federal law rules and regulation managed in-efficiently with a user interface (repo) having over 25k+ tests, 4k+ disparate information channels/sources/ legacy application with both structured/unstructured data and manual execution method containing numerous data wrangling processes using 3rd/4th/5th generation technologies

- TAAS (Testing As A Service)

Introduced consulting service for Front Line Unit (First Line of Defense) within EIT (Second line of defense)

- Micro-Innovations (Innovative Machine learning projects)
  - Unstructured to structured data conversion methods and ordering algorithm with stemming, lemmatization bag of words approach
  - Control environment for FOSS applications (python)
  - Encryption/ decryption of customer information
  - Fast risk alignment using topic modeling (NLP)
  - Network graph model on Federal law, rules & regulations
  - Markov chain transition matrix to identify two stages of risk in associate fraudulence and scenario identification
  - Document clustering based on OCR, Image processing, templates matching etc.

Business Analyst - Data Sciences

Snapdeal.com

Gurgaon, India

08/2015 - 08/2017

Key Projects:

Personalization & customer retention

- Improved Recommendation System to fit every customer
- Improved customer retention by 8% in less than 3 months
- Simplified customer profiling (8+ latent variables/ define customer profile for personalization)

Supply Chain Management efficiency

- Improved product pricing, logistic costing and reduce burn
- Improved "Expected goods to be purchased" model
- C-Suit Dashboards & Growth hacking
- Summarizing cross-selling/up-selling/retention cohorts/

customer journey/ conversion funnel/ promotion effectiveness - Improved sales by 200% (~65lacs/day) using experimental design

Senior Executive – Corporate Strategic Marketing

**HLC Technologies** 

Noida, India

06/2014 - 08/2015

Key Projects:

Delta Value Proposition Model

Feedback mechanism to understand the gaps between competitor offerings and our value proposition in commoditized industry Score micro-vertical/propositions (like SIAM, BServ etc.) using data of different types from multiple platform

ADM - Market Contract at Renewal

Created a logistic model to compute likelihood of winning and validated with empirical formulated Bid2Win probabilities

C-Suit & ROI Dashboard

Digital web performance dashboard | Deal mix report on RTB/CTB | Funnel moments | web content and brand measures

Ideations and Improvements:

- Revenue forecasting and budgeting using time series analysis
- Social Media Analytics and sentiment analysis using radian7
- Web content scoring model
- Attribution modeling on market channels

# SKILLS AND STRENGHTS



## **EDUCATION**

Indian Statistical Institute (ISI) – Kolkata/Assam

Post Graduate Diploma in Statistical Method and Application

2011 – 2012 (including Research Thesis)

University of Delhi

B.Sc. Applied Physical Sciences (Mathematical Computing)

2008 - 2011

### Awards and recognitions

2012 Indian Statistical Institute & NSSO, Awarded for the research work on amphibian population growth pattern & density estimation by former finance minister Shri. Pranab Mukherjee

### Language

